m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：歪椅  阿蘅阿蘅  非燕  Vero
翻译：小泡先森 灰灰  赛太公  YY猫
校对：像个傻瓜赛太公 不受控制YY猫   总监   YY
后期：孤帆    时间轴：加森  非燕
老爸老妈浪漫史
第八季  第十一集&第十二集
你们想喝点什么吗
Can I get you guys anything to drink?
-苏格兰威士忌  纯的  -厄运结
- Scotch, neat. - Jinx.
我的...  老天
Oh, my... God.
孩子们  你们可能难以理解为什么五个
Kids, you may be wondering why five adults
30多岁的成年人会对"厄运结"如此在意
in their 30s would take a jinx so seriously.
这都源于五年前的一天
It all started one day five years ago.
哦  范海辛[电影名]
Ooh, Van Helsing.
"厄运结"  你被下咒了
Jinx. You're jinxed.
所以从此刻起  你不能说一句话
That means that you can't speak until someone
直到目睹了厄运结之人说出你的姓名
who was present for the jinx says your name, or else
不然你就等着突遭横祸吧
you will have very bad luck.
简直是无稽之谈
That's ridiculous.
你把"厄运结"打破了
You broke the jinx.
马修  我是一个成熟的男人
Marshall, I'm a grown-ass man.
我还是公司的联合董事会成员
I'm on my building's co-op board.
当我说黑比诺红酒加上少许大黄
When I say a Pinot Noir tastes
这样品起来既奢华又不失泥土的芳香
luxuriously earthy with a hint of rhubarb,
我可不是胡诌的哦
I'm not faking it.
大黄是可食用的植物
我有不少床伴
I've had several
之前可都是基辛格的枕边人
of the same sexual partners as Henry Kissinger.
美国前国务卿
小小"厄运结"休想让我闭嘴
I'm not about to stop talking just because I was jinxed.
晚些时候
巴尼断了三根肋骨和两根脊椎骨
Barney broke three limbs and two vertebrae,
但"厄运结"  他再也不敢打破了
but he never broke another jinx.
事实上  他开始对"厄运结"走火入魔
In fact, he started taking jinxes way too seriously.
巴尼  我打通了体育电台
Barney, I'm on hold with Sports Talk AM
要跟儿时明尼苏达双城队中的偶像通电话啦
to talk to my childhood hero from the Minnesota Twins.
明尼苏达的棒球队
你的儿时偶像是谁啊
Who's your childhood hero?
-弗兰克・瓦奥拉[棒球明星]  -厄运结
- Frank Viola. Frank Viola - Jinx!
你好  我是弗兰克
Hello, this is Frank.
有人吗
Anyone there?
你好
Hello?
都听见你喘息声了  你个胆小鬼
I can hear you breathing, you coward.
所以当多年之后终于有人
So, when someone finally jinxed Barney
给巴尼下了"厄运结"的咒
for the first time in years,
我们都超级兴奋
we were pretty psyched.
恐怖魔王的统治结束啦
The reign of terror is over!
这根雪茄在我口袋里等了两年
I've had this cigar in my pocket for two years,
只为此刻
waiting for this moment.
两年前味道应该更好
Aw, that would've been good about two years ago.
干杯
Cheers.
好嘞  好嘞
Huzzah! Huzzah.
你这是想让我们说出你的名字
Oh, oh, oh, you want us to say your name
帮你解开"厄运结"吗
and un-jinx you?
想得美  老哥
I don't think so, pal.
这个"厄运结"要维持很久呢
This is gonna be a long jinx.
就像犹太赎罪日一样长[25小时]
Like Yom Kippur services long.
唯一的区别是  赎罪日得斋戒[很快]
The only difference is, Yom Kippur's a fast
而你的"厄运结"可要度日如年啦
and this one's gonna be a slow.
泰德
Now, Ted,
可否帮个忙来给我详细解释说一下
I was wondering if you could expand upon what you were saying
你之前提到的老钱币
earlier about antiquated currency.
对  对  对
Ah, yes, yes.
与普遍的认知恰恰相反
Contrary to popular belief,
早期五分镍币上的野牛是取材于
the buffalo nickel was modeled on
一头名叫"黑钻石"的野牛
the Black Diamond bison
而不是更具代表性的西部平原野牛
rather than the more iconic Western Plains bison.
换句话说
To wit,
如果塔夫脱总统也这么来的话
if President Taft had had his way,
五分镍币上就要印白鹭了
we'd all be talking about the egret nickel.
美国第27任总统  鸟类保护主义者
2012年的冬天
In the winter of 2012
我设计的摩天大楼就要投入使用了
the skyscraper that I designed was about to open,
这也不禁让我想起一位对我
which got me thinking about the most influential
影响最深的建筑学教授
architecture professor I ever had.
所以每当我们孙子的孙子问我们
So when the children of our grandchildren's children
"我们是何许人也"时
ask us "who were we,"
他们能在我们设计的建筑物
they'll find the answer carved
那块用花岗岩雕刻的诗篇中找到答案
into the granite poetry of our architecture.
好啦
Okay.
没有比这更棒的了
It doesn't get any better than that.
下课
Class dismissed.
太...  令人赞叹了
Wow, just wow.
有什么能帮你的吗
Do you need something?
我有个苹果
I have an apple
想着安安静静地吃
I was hoping to eat in silence.
好的  维尼克教授  我...
Of course, Professor Vinick, I, um,
我画了一份设计图
I-I sketched out a design,
你如果能过目一下就再好不过了
and it'd be such an honor if you took a look at it.
那好吧
Oh, well.
传言中
It is believed
法老们花了一百多年的时间
that it took the pharaohs over 100 years
才建起狮身人面像
to build the Sphinx.
那么
So...
你的意思是...
you think...
我该再多花点时间吗
I should spend more time on it?
我的老天  千万别
Oh, dear God, no.
这作品烂透了
This is terrible.
那你干嘛要提狮身人面像
Then, why'd you mention the Sphinx?
我的思绪常飘到狮身人面像上
I find my mind is often with the Sphinx.
话说回来  你永远也成不了建筑师
Anyway, you'll never be an architect.
你永远也成不了建筑师
You'll never be an architect.
You'll never be an architect!
你们猜怎么着
Well, guess what.
我给维尼克教授寄了
I sent Professor Vinick
我大楼开幕仪式的请帖
the invitation to the opening of my building,
让他看看我真的成为了一名建筑师
so he'll see that I did become an architect,
我也原谅他那些小气伤人的话了
and that I've moved past his petty, hurtful words.
都过去十五年了  你还耿耿于怀
Wow. 15 years later and you're still this obsessed.
如果维尼克教授无故失踪
Yeah, if Vinick ever goes missing,
警察绝对直奔你家地下室去找
the cops are gonna come looking for him in your basement.
绝对的  他就是泰德的"井底之囚"
Totally, he's Ted's pit guy.
你胆敢再乱说一句
How dare you?
还有那是啥意思
And what is that?
"井底之囚"就是那个
A pit guy is someone
让你耿耿于怀了许久
you've been obsessed with for so long...
让你发疯到一定程度的人
that it's driven you crazy enough
以至于你会把他们扔进地下室的井里
to throw them in a pit in your basement
就像电影《沉默的羔羊》里那样
like in The Silence of the Lambs.
我不会对他下此狠手的
I'm not gonna Silence of the Lambs him.
顶多我会学电影《菜鸟大反攻》那样
At most, I'd Revenge of the Nerds him.
虽然我觉得他同意
Though I don't see a scenario
和我进行五项全能这种桥段  压根不会上演
where he agrees to play me in a pentathlon.
我同意泰德
Yeah, I'm with Ted--
我实在是找不到一个让我
there is no one I hate enough
恨到要将其"囚于井底"的人
to throw into a pit.
干嘛
What?
当罗宾最看不顺眼的同事帕特里斯
When Robin's most hated coworker Patrice
和巴尼开始约会时
started dating Barney,
她一直耿耿于怀
she became obsessed.
帕特里斯  她绝对是你的"井底之囚"
Patrice, Patrice goes in your pit.
我都跟你们说了
Guys, I told you,
我对帕特里斯早就释怀了
I am done obsessing about Patrice.
她的事就丢一边吧
Just drop her.
-是把她丢进"井底"吧  -你够了
- Drop her in a pit. - Enough.
每人心中都有自己想丢入井底的人
We all have people that we would throw in our pits,
我也相信  肯定有人
and I'm sure we all have people
也想把我们丢进他们的"井"里
who would like to throw us in their pits.
对  如果马修或者我失踪了
Yeah, if Marshall or I ever go missing,
我告诉你们该去谁的地下室找
I'll tell you whose basement to look in.
达里尔・拉库尔特
Daryl LaCourte.
不
Oh, no.
是疯子达里尔
It's creepy Daryl.
趁他没看见我们  赶快走
Let's get out of here before he sees us.
烫手沙包  快接
Hey, hot sack coming through.
好啊  达里尔
Hi, Daryl.
感觉好久没见到你们了呢
I feel like I never see you guys anymore.
每次我去参加派对  你们都正好要走
Like whenever I'm getting to a party, you're just leaving.
即使是办在你家的派对
Even that party at your place--
你们也是七点半就不见人影了
you guys just raced off into the night at 7:30.
太奇怪了
That's weird.
不过这下好了
But this is great--
沙包三剑客重聚首
the three hackmigos back together again.
达里尔  我们就大一时一起玩过一次沙包球
We played Hacky Sack together once freshman year, Daryl.
只玩过一次
Once.
1996年11月14号
November 14, 1996.
我人生中最棒的回忆
That is the best memory ever.
当然
Sure.
一辈子的沙包三剑客
The three hackmigos for life.
我们至今还会收到他寄来的电邮和卡片
To this day, we are still getting e-mails and posts from Daryl.
我们上传的所有小马文的照片
He has commented on every photo
他每一张都会评论
of Baby Marvin we have ever posted,
然后
and then
瞧瞧你们的沙包球球
哈大笑玩包
边哈哈大笑边在玩沙包
他还要评论自己的评论
he comments on his own comments.
各位  瞧  是巴...
Hey, guys, look, it's Bar...
没门  全世界我最爱的
none, my favorite non-speaking
中咒倒霉蛋
jinxed person in the world.
你今天过得如何啊
How was your day?
我来告诉你们我今天的遭遇
你们这群混蛋
我花了一个小时
也没能给司机说清楚我要去哪里
所以我因为迟到被大骂一顿
他们问周末谁没空来上班
我却什么也不能说
这就是我的周末
以万能的真命天女组合之名
almighty destiny's child
求求你们了
说我的名字
啊哦  我完全没懂他在说啥
Yeah, I didn't get a word of that.
对不起  兄弟
Sorry, buddy.
特布罗斯基  这是我一年中最喜欢的时刻
Ah, Scherbatsky, it's my favorite time of year.
我不知道你这么喜欢圣诞节
Didn't know you liked Christmas so much.
不  我说的是年终总结
No, year-end reviews.
我们可以炒人呢
We get to fire some people.
快跟我一起开心
Get into the spirit.
桑迪  你可能很享受因微小的个人分歧
Look, Sandy, you might enjoy firing people
而炒人鱿鱼的事
for petty personal differences.
把性病传染给我
I'd hardly call giving me gonorrhea
可不是什么微小的个人分歧
a petty personal difference.
蛋我可是专业人士
But I am a professional,
我不会因不专业的原因解雇员工
and I would never fire someone for unprofessional reasons.
反正一定得有人被炒就是了
Well, somebody's got to go.
孩子们  有时"井底之囚"
Kids, the thing about pit people,
是得等你有机会把他们推进去时
sometimes you don't even know you have one
你才会意识到有这么一个人
until you have a chance to push 'em in.
罗宾
Hi, Robin.
想都别想  兄弟
Not happening, bro.
手酸了吗
Hand get tired?
想都别想  兄弟
Not happening, bro.
我手里拿的是
I hold in my hand
维尼克教授的回函
the RSVP from Professor Vinick.
他选了"不会出席"那一项  不过没事
Ah, he's checked "Will not attend," which is fine,
只要他知道有这么一回事就行了
because all I needed to know was that he knows.
现在这回函我扔了也行  不用再看了
So now I will throw this in the trash and never look at it.
她谢了什么
What's this?
"你肯定寄错了人"
"I believe you've sent this to the wrong person.
"我不认识泰德・莫斯比"
I have no idea who Ted Mosby is."
你会记起我的  维尼克教授
Oh, you'll remember who I am, Professor Vinick.
你绝不会忘记
You'll never forget it.
想都别想  兄弟
Not happening, bro.
泰德  我们和你一起去卫斯理大学
Ted, just because we're coming with you to Wesleyan
并不意味着我们接受你的行为
does not mean that we condone your behavior.
我们只是当做来重游母校
Just using it as an excuse to see the old campus...
以及避免错过看你精神彻底崩溃的机会
and maybe watch you have a complete mental breakdown.
你见到维尼克教授之后  打算干嘛
What are you even gonna do when you see Professor Vinick?
容我细细道来
Oh, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
我的弗兰克・ 盖里和弗兰克・劳埃德・赖特啊
Sweet merciful Franks Gehry and Lloyd Wright,
两者皆为著名建筑师
这是出自哪位大师之手的神作啊
from what brilliant mind was this work of art sired?
莫斯比
Mosby.
泰德・莫斯比
Ted Mosby.
建筑师
Architect.
但这  这...
But that's-that's...
不可能吗
Impossible?
看来你当年看错了  维尼克
Looks like you were wrong, Vinick.
罪该万死的大错
Dead wrong.
不
No!
注意点  泰德
Be careful, Ted.
复仇美梦往往不会成真
Revenge fantasies never work out the way you want.
尤其是跟跳舞有关的复仇
Especially dance-based revenge.
我的毕业舞会一把辛酸泪啊
My prom was rough, guys.
我们就快到了
Ooh! We're almost there.
我等不及想看看母校了
Oh, I can't wait to see the old campus.
我要去吃食堂的巨型热狗
I'm gonna grab one of those giant dining hall hot dogs.
我爱死那个大香肠了
Oh, I love those huge wieners.
你好像没听清楚啊
I'm not so sure you heard me.
我说  我爱死"大香肠"了
I said, "I love those huge wieners."
我喜欢得不得了
I love them.
喜欢放自己嘴里
In my mouth.
问你几个问题  克拉丽斯...帕特里斯
So, let me ask you a few questions, Clarice... Patrice.
克拉丽斯  《沉默的羔羊》女主角
你给这半年来自己的表现
How would you rate your performance
打多少分
in the last six months?
我不喜欢讨论自己
Well, I don't like to talk about myself,
但是我的同事们都应该得超超优
but all my coworkers deserve an A-double-plus,
那是肯定的
that's for suresies.
高档的乳液
Fancy lotion.
这牌子乳液都放篮子里呢
It puts the lotion in the basket.
这乳液真的特别好
It's just, this is really nice lotion.
这篮子也很好看  罗宾
And what a pretty basket, Robin.
我知道  所以我才买啊  帕特里斯
I know, that's why I bought it, Patrice!
-天啊  感觉一切都没变  -对啊
- Oh, man, it's like nothing has changed. - Mmm, I know.
小面包  佐料
The bun, the relish.
那是个膝盖
That's a knee.
画得很棒的膝盖[尼]  所以呢
It's a beautifully drawn knee, so?
这是谷仓[巴]
That's a barn.
原来是膝盖仓库[尼巴]啊
Oh, knee barn, right.
真是个好主意  莉莉
That's a great idea, Lily.
回家路上  我们应该在膝盖谷仓停一下
On the way home, we should stop at the knee barn,
-买点批发的膝盖  -没错
- pick us up some wholesale knees. - Yeah.
马修  莉莉
Marshall? Lily!
你们...你们来了
You... you're here.
-你好啊  达里尔  -你好啊  达里尔
- Hi, Daryl. - Hi, Daryl.
你们也好啊
Hi.
过了这么多年
After all these years.
你们跟我画的样子都还一模一样
You look just like you do in my paintings.
来抱抱啊  你们俩
Come here, guys.
世上有人  亦有神
There are men and there are gods.
安东尼・高迪[建筑师]  是人神合一
Antoni Gaudi Was both.
世上有蠢人和贱人
There are jerk faces and there are buttholes.
维尼克教授  是蠢贱合一
Professor Vinick was both.
这句真妙啊  泰德
Good one, Ted.
快点  维尼克  让我有机会开场
Come on, Vinick, give me an opening.
高迪的建筑表达出
Gaudi's architecture gave expression
自然界无规律的几何形状
to the anarchic geometric form of nature.
"高迪的建筑风格"
"Gaudi's architecture..."
其实这点还真不错呢
Actually, that's a really good point.
维尼克教授 *
* Wow, Professor Vinick
你让我受益良多 *
* Man, you taught me so much
无论是建筑还是人生 *
* About architecture and life
你的课酷毙了 *
* God, your lectures are so cool
我要让你刮目相看  并与你成为至交 *
* I'll earn your respect and we'll be best friends.
没有比这更棒的了
Okay, it doesn't get any better than that.
的确是没更棒的了
No, it doesn't.
你在这里干什么  达里尔
What are you doing here, Daryl?
我就住在这条街上
Well, I live right down the street.
可我就在这里工作
But I work right here.
天啊
Whoa. Oh, boy.
沙包三剑客
那些是...
Are those...
照着我们的脸画的吗  伙计
...our, our faces up there, buddy?
那还用问
Hack, yeah!
不是我们共同想出的
It was just as much your idea as mine
在卫斯理大学开一家沙包球店的主意吗
to open up a Hacky Sack store here at Wesleyan.
所以你从没离开过这里啊
So you never left?
就离开过一次  我在广告网上认识个女孩
Once. I met a girl on Craigslist,
然后飞去波士顿见她
and I flew to Boston to meet her.
结果她是个男人  体重300磅  还把我给抢了
She was a man, 300 pounds, and robbed me.
不过那仍是我生命中最美好的一晚
Still, the best night of my life.
不过现在不是了
Until now!
我们沙包三剑客又聚一起了
The three hackmigos back together again!
我一直等着给你们点东西  等了好久好久
You know, I've been waiting forever to give you something.
你们跟我回家
You're coming with me to my house,
不许拒绝我哦
and I'm not taking no for an answer.
兄弟  你的机会来了
Dude, this is your chance.
快帮我解咒  我会帮你摆脱这场恶心的噩梦
Set me free, and I will lie you out of this creepy nightmare.
真难抉择
This is a tough one.
一方面  我们可能会送命
On the one hand, we might die.
另一方面  你被下咒了
On the other, you're jinxed.
帮我解咒  马修
Let me free, Marshall.
这家伙可能会施暴哦
This guy could be violent.
施暴  瓦奥拉[音似]
Violent... Viola...
弗兰克・瓦奥拉
Frank Viola.
我们非常乐意去你家  达里尔
We would love to come to your house, Daryl!
真好
Yeah!
好
Okay, um...
你和巴尼多久做一次
how often are you and Barney doing it?
这个问题怪怪的  罗宾
That's a strange question, Robin.
没错
You're right.
或许我该走了
Maybe I should leave.
对  或许你是该走了
Yeah, maybe you should.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
太...  令人赞叹了
Wow. Just wow.
我叫泰德・莫斯比  你以前的学生
Ted Mosby. I'm a former student of yours.
我真的成为一名建筑师了
You know, I actually became an architect.
你对我有印象吗
Any chance you remember me?
请见谅  我教了20年书
Oh, please excuse me, I've been teaching for over 20 years.
大家的脸我都分不清了
All the faces start to blend together
除非你长着很奇怪的胡子或别的
unless you have a, a weird mustache or, or something.
我大一那年试着留胡子
Junior year I tried to grow muttonchops,
可大家一直说我的脸太恶心了
but people kept saying my face made them nauseous.
其实不是大家  是你
Well, not people. You.
总之  我希望你能赏脸
Anyway, I would be honored if you,
看看我设计的大楼
if you took a look at my building.
这大楼
This...
真丑
is hideous.
你永远成不了建筑师
You'll never be an architect.
你永远成不了建筑师  你永远成不了建筑师
You'll never be an architect. You'll never be an architect!
你永远成不了建筑师
You'll never be an architect.
等等  我搞错了
Wait. I was mistaken.
你绝对会成为一名出色的建筑师
You most definitely will be an architect.
真的吗
Really?
这简直是惊人之作
These are astonishing,
八字胡皮特
Handlebar Pete.
所以你说的"你家里的惊喜"
So, when you said "surprise in your house,"
实际上指的是  "你家灯光微弱
what you really meant was "surprise in the poorly lit
没装窗户的地下室里的惊吓"吗
windowless basement of your house."
你们一定会喜欢我为你们准备的惊喜
Oh, you guys are gonna love what I have to show you.
我无比激动  都想号啕大哭
I am so excited, I could just cry
然后放声大笑  大声尖叫
and laugh and scream
再不停地锤墙
and just punch the wall over and over
一而再再而三地锤
and over and over and over!
我们能不能
Could we just see it,
去楼上客厅看啊
like, up in the living room
或者去不那么阴森的地方看
or anywhere less... gimp-storagey?
我刚意识到
I just realized
我想拍照留念
I want to take a picture of this.
我想把你们的脸放在壁炉架上  像战利品那样
I want to put your faces on my mantel like a trophy.
我的战利品
Like a trophy!
我来了
Here I come.
不  我们不想要你的惊喜  达里尔
No! We don't want your surprise, Daryl!
我们不是你的朋友
We're not your amigos,
我们更不是你的沙包剑客
we're definitely not your hackmigos.
在你谋杀我们之前
And before you murder us,
你应该知道我们还有个孩子
you should know that we have a child!
他估计都有八九个孩子了
He probably has eight or nine!
什么  谋杀
What? Murder?
我是想给你们一张支票
I wanted to give you a check.
10万块支票
For $100,000...
毕竟沙包三剑客是我们一起想出的点子
for coming up with the idea of the Three Hackmigos with me.
我把你们带到这来  是想展示下我的存货
I brought you down here to show you all my inventory.
生意好得不行
Business has really exploded.
我就像是乐队演出与停车场运动
I mean, I'm sort of the Mark Zuckerberg
项目上的马克・扎克伯格[Facebook创始人]
of jam-band concert parking lot athletics.
不过等一下
Well, second.
但你逃不掉的  杂耍魔鬼棍阿荣
But I'm coming for you, Devil Stick Ron.
你为什么要解雇我
Why would you fire me?
因为没有人该活得像你一样开心
Because nobody should be as happy as you are.
还有你的饼干  也仅仅是还不赖而已
And also your cookies... they're only pretty good.
罗宾  真是因为我的工作吗
Robin, is this really about me?
不  不是
No, it's not.
"炒了再上"的老戏码啊
The old "fire and bang."
向你致敬  特布罗斯基
Respect, Scherbatsky.
很不错吧  对吗  八字胡皮特
Pretty good, right? Right, Handlebar Pete?
你蓄着那迷人的小胡子挺占便宜的啊
Ah, you got it easy with that sweet, sweet 'stache.
泰德  我看见你拿着你大楼的小模型
Hey, Ted, I see you're holding a little version of your building
对陌生人大吼大叫
and yelling at strangers.
我猜你复仇十分"顺利"吧
So I assume it all worked out?
我是想到  既然我在一座
I realized, since I work in a
三维立体的建筑里工作
three-dimensional medium,
那真正能在维尼克面前展示的方式
the only way to really stick it to Vinick would be
应该是用三维立体模型
with a three-dimensional model.
无论你怎么做  不要在进场的时候
Whatever you do, don't march in there
想着"我要表演虫舞
thinking, "I'm gonna do the worm.
肯定轰动全场"
That'll show 'em!"
说真的  各位
Seriously, guys,
当年我舞会的惨痛教训不得不再三提醒啊
I can't stress enough how bad my prom was.
说起当年...
Speaking of the past...
我们简直像白痴一样  对不起
Wow, we feel like idiots. We're sorry.
老实说  没关系
You know, honestly, it's fine.
看看我现在多意气风发
Look how great I'm doing.
看看我取得的成就  我不需要
Look at what I've built. I don't need
获得什么大学同学的认可
the validation of some people from college
来肯定自己
to feel good about myself.
我的人生棒极了
My life is amazing!
我跟P-放克乐队一起拥有
I own a timeshare
圣巴兹岛别墅的分时享用权
in St. Barts with P-Funk!
-跟整支乐队吗  -对啊
- The, the whole band? - Yeah.
你们会一起玩音乐吗
Do you guys jam?
玩个不停啊
That's all we do.
你们彻底拒绝了
So, you completely rejected
一个对你们念念不忘
the guy who's been obsessing
长达16年的人  而他就这么算了吗
about you for 16 years, and he was okay with it?
疯子达里尔比我更能调整自己的情绪啊
Is creepy Daryl more emotionally adjusted than I am?
孩子们  人生有些时候
Kids, sometimes in life
你会在脑中为某人挖一座井
you'll make a pit for someone in your mind.
但最后  唯一在井里的那个人只会是自己
But ultimately the only person in that pit is yourself.
对不起
I'm sorry.
只是看见你和巴尼在一起
Just seeing you with Barney has brought up
让我想起了一些往事
some old feelings, and I...
我真的不喜欢多愁善感
I really don't like feelings.
但这不是你的错  或巴尼的错
But that's not your fault or Barney's fault.
只是看见你跟他在一起  真的很难受
It's just really hard seeing you with him.
这意味着只有一个人
Which means there's only one person
能将你从井里解救出去
who can let you out of the pit.
你炒了帕特里斯吗
So you fired Patrice?
不  她留下
No, she's staying.
我们走吧  大伙们
Let's get out of here, guys.
莫斯比先生
Oh, Mr. Mosby.
你给自己的大楼建了模型
You built a model of your building.
没有
No.
为什么  为了证明什么吗
Why? To prove some sort of point?
真是可悲
This is just sad.
不不  我刚打算要把它扔了呢
No, no, I was just throwing it out.
是啊  谁信啊
Sure, you were.
不
No!
不  我刚经历了一个超然的瞬间
No, I-I-I had a transcendent moment
找到了情感上的释然
where I found emotional clarity!
我知道大声嚷嚷
And I realize shouting that
听起来不像是真话  但确实如此
makes it seem like it's not true, but I did!
好吧  我们要去买点零食
Yeah, we're gonna grab some snacks.
你们要点什么
You guys want anything?
辣牛肉干
Spicy beef jerky.
完全明白你意思
Got you loud and clear.
我的天啊  巴尼
Oh, my God! Barney!
你解了我的咒
You unjinxed me!
我自由了  如果硬币上的野牛
I'm free! If the bison on the nickel
听到你这么说它们
could hear you talk about them,
它们会自我加剧灭绝的脚步
they would diminish their population even further on purpose.
如果莉莉想嘴里塞根"大香肠"
If Lily wants a big wiener in her mouth,
她可以找我
she's got my number.
抱歉  这一路上车上有人放屁的罪
And I'm sorry that you took the rap for all the farting on
都让你顶了  其实是我放的
the car ride up here. That was me!
戒指  这是什么戒指
The ring! What's, what's, what's the ring?
对了  戒指  我打算向帕特里斯求婚
Right, the ring. I'm gonna ask Patrice to marry me.
你说真的吗
Are you serious?
"厄运结"  很好
Jinx! Good!
我得保证我说这些话时  你不插嘴
I need to say some things without you interrupting.
对  我是认真的
Yes, I am serious.
我知道如果你现在能说话
I know that if you could talk,
你会说我疯了
you'd say that I'm crazy
或说我矫枉过正  说我进展太快了
or that I'm overcorrecting or that I'm moving too fast.
但你错了
But you would be wrong.
整个三角洲地带所有的浪货
Look, I have banged my way through every bimbo
我都睡过了  但睡过之后
in the tristate area, and it left me
内心除了破碎  就没其他感觉了
feeling nothing but, but broken.
但现在  跟帕特里斯一起
But now, with Patrice,
我人生中第一次  感到安定和快乐
for the first time in my life, I feel settled and happy.
我想这么过一辈子
I want to feel this way forever.
所以明天晚上
So tomorrow night on the roof
在环球新闻大楼的屋顶
of the World Wide News building--
那是帕特里斯最喜欢的地方
that's Patrice's favorite spot--
我要向她求婚
I'm gonna ask her to marry me.
不许说话  你被下咒了
Ah, poot-tu-tat! You're jinxed.
如果你愿遵守以下两条规矩  我就给你解咒
I'll unjinx you if you'll follow these two rules:
第一  你不能试图劝我放弃
one you can't try to talk me out of it,
第二  你不能告诉任何人  同意吗
two you can't tell anybody. Agreed?
这可是以"厄运结"起誓  如果你食言了
It's a jinx swear, so if you break it,
我就可以用威浮球球棒
I get to hit you in the nuts three times
威浮球  一种空心棒球
朝你的蛋蛋猛击三下
with a Wiffle ball bat.
谢谢你  泰德
Thank you... Ted.
好啊  各位
Hi, guys!
不  你中了"厄运结"的啊
No. But you're jinxed!
带着要给你们的惊喜哦
And I've got your surprise right here!
我引诱泰德叫了我的名字
I tricked Ted into saying my name.
不是吧  泰德
Aw, come on, Ted!
"厄运结"  "厄运结"
Jinx! Jinx!
恐怖魔王的统治归来了
The reign of terror is back!
如果你们不想我在车里抽烟
Hey, if you guys don't want me to smoke
或放屁  但说无妨
or fart in here, just speak up.
没意见吗  很好
Nothing? Great.
谢谢你们给我买辣牛肉干啦
Thanks for the spicy beef jerky, dude.
不管怎样  现在安静会挺好的
Anyway, I think we could all use a little quiet.
除非你有什么想说的吗  泰德
Unless you have something you want to talk about, Ted?
没有
No.
想都别想  伙计
Not happening, bro.
于是我答应巴尼  不告诉任何人
So I had promised not to tell anyone
他要向帕特里斯求婚的事
about Barney's plan to propose to Patrice.
但我心里明白  罗宾有权知道此事
But I knew deep down Robin deserved to know.
看啊  他在这儿呢
Uh, there he is!
纽约城历史上
The youngest architect ever
建造摩天大楼最年轻的建筑师
to build a skyscraper in New York City!
到现在居然还是单身的泰德・莫斯比
The shockingly still single Ted Mosby.
听见了吗  女士们
You hear that, ladies?
真不敢相信巨人银行大楼今晚就投入使用了
I can't believe the GNB Tower opens tonight.
泰德  世界终于要看到你的创世巨作了
Ted, your building finally gets unveiled to the whole world.
听见了吗  女士们
You hear that, ladies?!
紧张吗
Nervous?
我现在不只流汗流尿  屎也用流的了
Everything comes out of my body in liquid form now.
别听这句  女士们
Ignore that, ladies.
另外  我一直在做一个噩梦
Plus, I, I keep having this nightmare
梦见金刚在剪彩典礼上出现
where King Kong shows up to the opening
却不愿意爬上我的大楼
but refuses to climb my building
他说  "这楼修得太不怎么样了"
because, in his words, "It's a bit derivative."
别瞎想了  今晚会精彩绝伦的
Oh, stop it, tonight is gonna be amazing.
我们到时会给你敬酒致辞
And we are definitely gonna be there to toast you,
但如果可以  我们可能会提早离开
but we might have to leave a little early if that's okay.
我爸爸给了我们史无前例的超赞圣诞礼
My dad just gave us the most amazing Christmas gift ever.
马文出生后  我们第一次可以夜不归宿
Our first night away since Marvin was born.
24小时不用看见那小混蛋了
24 hours straight without that little bastard.
这故事真不错  回头等马文长大了
This will be a nice memory to share with Marvin
犹豫要不要送你们去老人院时
when he's older and deciding whether or not
我就讲给他听
to put you in a home.
我们很需要放个假了
Hey, we need this.
为了尽可能地节约时间
We're maximizing our time away
我们把每项安排的时间都精确到分钟了
by planning everything down to the minute.
看见没
See?
中午12点  劝说泰德
12 P..-- guilt Ted
同意让我们今晚可以早退
into saying it's okay if we leave early tonight.
你们今晚可以早退啦
It's okay if you leave early tonight.
你们在我的大日子能过来一趟
Look, I just appreciate you showing up at all
我已经很感激了
on your big night away.
巴尼就根本不会来
I mean, Barney's not even gonna be there.
怎么会
What?
今晚是你职业生涯上最重要的一晚
This is the biggest night of your career.
巴尼为什么不来啊
Why isn't Barney coming?
我不清楚  他只说
I don't know-- he said,
"传奇"  "接受挑战"  然后眨了个眼
"legendary" and "challenge accepted," and then he winked.
"等等"之类的
"wait for it,"  you know, all that stuff.
听起来是挺像他的
That does sound like him.
我们是你的真朋友
Well, we're your real friends
说什么也不会错过今晚的
and we wouldn't miss it for the world.
所以今晚我们会在7点03到那里
That is why we will see you tonight
然后7点14分走人
from 7:03 to 7:14.
-回见啦  -拜
- Bye, guys. - Bye.
巴尼究竟为什么不来
Okay, what's the real reason Barney's not coming?
我本可以趁此机会告诉罗宾巴尼的事
Here was my chance to tell Robin about Barney.
其实巴尼没说他今晚有什么安排
Yeah, actually, Barney didn't say what he was doing tonight.
但我今天晚上没有女伴
Anyway, uh, you know, I'm not taking anyone to the opening,
你愿意当我女伴吗
so you want to be my date?
当然
Sure.
爸爸  我给你写了一张单子
Okay, Dad, I-I made you a list
是马文晚上的注意事项  精确到分钟了哦
of Marvin's nightly schedule down to the minute.
好的
Okay.
下午六点  换上可食用内衣
Night, 06 P.M.-- put on edible underwear."
拿错单子了  弄错了
Wrong list, wrong list.
别紧张嘛
Come on, relax.
我对这小家伙了如指掌
I know this little guy like the back of my hand.
上帝啊  我掌后这是啥玩意
Dear Lord, what is that?
原来是果酱
Oh, jam, okay.
果酱而已
Just jam.
我忘记教你摇篮曲了
Oh, I-I forgot the lullaby.
你知道马文的专属摇篮曲吗
Do you know Marvin's lullaby?
我们每天晚上都唱给他听
We sing it to him every night.
晚安  晚安  小马文 *
* Night, night, little Marvin
天上星星为你闪 *
* Stars twinkle for you
梦界火车嘎嚓飞 *
* The Dreamland train's a-chuggin'
你的梦想皆实现 *
* All your dreams will come true
小马说晚安 *
* And the horsie says, "Good night"
鸟儿说晚安 *
* And the birdie says, "Good night"
大象说晚安 *
* And the elephant says, "Good night"
骷髅弹肋骨说晚安 *
* And the skeleton playing his own rib cage says, "Good Night"
机器人说晚安 *
* And the robot says, "Good night"
晚安 *
* Good night.
吵死了  别唱了
Enough with the damn music!
纳斯比先生说晚安 *
* And Mr. Nesbit says, "Good night"
全世界都说晚安 *
* And the whole world says, "Good night"
该你了  妈咪
Take it, Mommy.
明白  给他喂点止咳糖浆
Got it-- load him up with cough syrup,
等他昏睡过去后看《绝命毒师》
watch Breaking Bad until he conks out.
开玩笑的啦
Just kidding.
我们成功了
We did it.
没错
Yeah, we did.
我们出家门了
Now that we're out the door,
而且我一点也不焦虑
I actually don't feel anxious.
天啊  是你爸
Whoa, oh, my God, it's your dad!
肯定有惨事发生了
Oh, something horrible happened-- aah!
是泰德  别紧张
Oh, it's Ted, relax.
酒吧  现在
Bar, now.
怎么了
What is it?
他要我过去
He needs me.
宝贝  那我们神奇浪漫的夜晚怎么办呀
But, baby, what about our magical romantic night?
我们本该在四分钟后
In four minutes we're supposed to
在出租车里开始"毛手毛脚"呢
be doing hand stuff in the cab.
我会尽快的  肯定没什么大事
I'll be quick-- I'm sure it's nothing huge.
这可是大事
That's huge.
是啊  所以今晚巴尼来不了了
Yeah, that's why Barney's not coming tonight.
他要求婚
He's getting engaged.
而且我知道我得告诉罗宾
And I knew that I had to tell Robin.
但是呢
But?
我好像...
I may have, uh...
邀请她当我今晚的女伴了
asked her to be my date instead.
我脑子到底哪里有病啊
What is wrong with me?
我心深处
Deep down,
是不是有个疯狂的我
is there still some crazy part of me
认为我和罗宾还有希望
that thinks I'm gonna wind up with Robin?
我就那么逃避现实吗
Am I that deluded?
如果真是如此  我得成熟起来
If so, I need to grow up.
对了  我现在算违背了"厄运结"誓言
Oh, um, by the way, I'm breaking a jinx swear here,
可别告诉巴尼  不然他可以
so don't tell Barney or he gets to whack me
用威浮球球棒狠打我的蛋蛋三次呢
in the nuts three times with a Wiffle ball bat.
行  这些都不为过
Sure, pretty standard.
罗宾值得拥有去追回巴尼的最后一次机会
Robin deserves the chance to go after Barney one last time
只要她也心之所愿
if that's what she wants.
谢谢  哥们
Thanks, buddy.
说出来舒服多了
This helped.
那我去告诉她啦
I'm gonna go tell her.
等等  有件事
One quick thing.
别去
Don't.
真棒啊
Wow. Nice.
现在到了这儿  我就没觉得那么焦虑了
You know, now that I'm here, I don't feel that anxious.
是我爸  肯定发生了什么惨事
It's my dad-- something horrible's happened!
是我丈夫  放轻松
My husband, relax.
宝贝  我还得一会才能回去
Hey, um, I'm gonna be a little while, baby.
说来话长  但泰德需要我的帮助
It's a long story, but Ted needs my help.
好吧  但是快点
Okay, but hurry
不然我就自己做第十一条了
or I'm gonna start doing Number 11 on my own.
你能自己做"那个"啊
You can do that by yourself?
姐练过瑜伽  小贱人
Pilates, bitch.
好吧  那为什么我不该告诉罗宾
Okay, why shouldn't I tell Robin?
因为你内心深处有个疯狂的你
Because deep down some crazy part of you
仍然认为你和罗宾有希望  我同意这点
still thinks you're gonna wind up with her, and I agree.
-马修  -很抱歉  我就是支持泰德的
- Marshall... - I'm sorry, I'm Team Tedward.
以前是  现在是  永远都是
Always have been, always will be.
听着
Now, listen.
我想要我最好的朋友能幸福
I want my best friend to be happy.
如果罗宾就是你的幸福
And if Robin could mean happiness for you,
那老天  你为什么要帮她去追另一个男人啊
then, dear God, why help her go after another man?
因为她可能还爱着他
Because she might still be in love with him.
如果我不告诉她  不给她机会
To not tell her, to not give her that chance,
就太自私了
it's... it's selfish.
那就自私一回吧
So be selfish.
我做不到
I can't do that.
跟我分吃洋葱圈时  你怎么就不这么"无私"
Tell that to the onion rings we just "split."
罗宾是我的朋友
Robin is my friend.
她一直不只是朋友  你心里清楚
She's always been more than that and you know it.
现在  就在我们讲话之际
Now, as we speak,
我妻子正在酒店房间对我不忠
my wife is in a hotel room cheating on me...
跟自己出轨
with herself.
但我死也不会走
But I'm not leaving here
除非你答应我
until you promise not to say
你绝不会跟罗宾透露半句
a word about this to Robin.
跟着我念  "我..."
Now repeat after me. "I..."
可以一次多几个词  我应付得来
Well, I can do more at a time than "I."
"我  泰德・莫斯比  发誓
"I, Ted Mosby, promise to stop
不再把别人的利益置于身前
putting everyone else's interests ahead of my own,
在一生中就那么一次  为自己着想"
and for once in my life, do what's best for me."
我...
I...
抱歉  其他是什么来着
Sorry, what was the rest of that?
爸爸  我从我们的美妙之夜里
Hey, Dad, just taking a break
偷个空来问个好
from our amazing night to check in.
我不在马文一定情绪很低落吧
I bet Marvin's pretty devastated that I'm not there, huh?
完全没有  我觉得他都没意识到你不在
Not at all-- I don't think he even noticed you're gone.
感觉是"妈咪  那谁啊"的感觉
It's kind of like Mommy who?
那很好
Oh... oh, good.
但是以防万一  我还是给他在电话里
But I should probably sing him his nighttime lullaby
唱睡前摇篮曲吧
over the phone, just in case.
给他唱过了  唱得超棒呢
Sang it already-- nailed it.
你学小马了吗
Did you do the horsie?
-学了  -小鸟呢
- Yep. - The birdie?
-学了  -大象呢
- Yep. - Elephant?
-学了  -麋鹿呢
- Yep. - Moose.
没有麋鹿  少唬我
No moose, trick question.
机器人呢
Robot.
我要挂了
Look, I should go.
马文在我怀里睡觉呢
Marvin's asleep in my arms.
他的头闻起来都是爱的味道
Mmm, his head smells like love.
再见
Bye.
所以孩子们  在这个寒冷的十二月夜里
And so, kids, on that cold December night
我决定接受你们马修叔叔的建议
I decided to take your Uncle Marshall's advice
自私一点
and be a little selfish.
你好  真是美呆啦
Hello... and hubba-hubba.
谢谢
Aw, thanks.
但今晚的超级男主角可是莫斯比哦
But tonight is about my main man Mosby.
是吗  为什么啊
Really? Why?
泰德  告诉兰吉特
Oh, Ted, tell Ranjit
今晚要发生的那件大事啊
the huge thing that's happening tonight.
巴尼要订婚了
Barney's getting engaged.
兰吉特退场
Ranjit out.
巴  巴尼要订婚了吗
Bar-Barney's getting engaged?
他让我保密
He asked me to keep it a secret,
但我觉得你应该知道
but I thought you deserved to know...
以免你想做些什么
in case you wanted to do something about it.
你想吗
Do you?
你想吗  罗宾
Do you, Robin?
兰吉特  给点私人空间好吗
Ranjit, a little privacy, please?
抱歉  我没在听哦
Sorry, not listening.
好啊  泰德  这地高低不平
Nice, uneven floor there, Ted.
莉莉  你喝醉了吗
Lily, are you drunk?
什么  我在度假
What? I... I'm on vacation.
我撬开小酒柜来喝两杯也不为过啊
I may have cracked open the minibar to celebrate.
这缉毒警谁找来的啊
Who invited the Narc?
听着  我知道你想马文
Hey, listen, I know that you miss Marvin,
但是这种正装宴会上我们也没办法
but it's not like we could've brought him
带他一起来啊
to a black tie event anyway.
没有童装版燕尾服可以给他穿啊
I don't think that they make tuxedo onesies.
我是说  没有帅气的童装燕尾服嘛
I mean, at least not ones that are in style.
还打蝴蝶领结
I mean, a bow tie?
现在难道还是98年吗
Is it 1998 already?
那些父母弱爆了  真粘娃
Yeah, these parents are so lame and-and clingy.
该学会放手了吧  你们俩废柴
Yeah, it's like, cut the cord already, right, guys?
对啊  那宝宝也一点都不可爱
Yeah, yeah, that baby's not even cute.
超级丑娃
Super ugly baby.
看样子就想吐
It's almost physically repulsive.
这下好了  我都开始分泌乳汁了
Great, I just started lactating.
我也是
Me, too.
那你打算怎么办
So, what do you want to do?
罗宾  我不想多管闲事
Robin, I do not want to meddle,
但是有首经典恋歌就是这样...
but this is like the classic love song says...
兰吉特
Ranjit.
兰吉特  从现在开始我们还是用短信交流吧
Ranjit, let's just communicate via text from now on, okay?
感谢你做的一切
I appreciate what you're doing.
但我再也不想去争取巴尼了
But I'm not chasing after Barney anymore.
我已厌倦如此为爱癫狂了
I-I just got done being crazy about all that.
我为何要再跳回那万劫不复的深渊呢
I mean, why would I want to throw myself back in that pit?
因为你还爱着他
Because you're in love with him.
不  我不爱了
No, I'm not.
我替他感到高兴
I'm happy for him.
所以巴尼・斯丁森将要在环球新闻大楼顶
So, it doesn't bother you that Barney Stinson's gonna propose
对另一个女人求婚  你都不介意吗
to another woman on top of the World Wide News building?
等等  为什么要在我公司大楼顶求婚啊
Wait, why the top of the World Wide News building?
我猜那是帕特里斯最爱的地方吧
I guess it's Patrice's favorite spot in the city.
我靠  帕特里斯  那是我最爱的地方
Damn it, Patrice, that's my favorite spot in the city!
激动啊...
Whoa.
兰吉特也说"激动啊"
Ranjit says, "Whoa."
好啦
Okay...
这小细节可能让我有点不爽
maybe that one detail stings a little bit,
但并不表示我还爱着巴尼啊
but that doesn't mean I'm in love with Barney.
"她一听就还爱着巴尼"
"Sounds like she's in love with Barney."
这分隔板有任何一点隔音效果吗
Okay, is this divider even slightly soundproof?
"当然有"
"Yes."
还发了个眨眼的符号
With a little winky face.
我诚心祝福巴尼幸福
Look, I... I hope it goes well for Barney.
我真心祝福他
I really do.
但今晚除了你的大楼
But tonight there is no place I would rather be
我哪都不会去
than at your building.
陪你庆祝
Celebrating with you.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
兰吉特  去西区泰德的超酷大楼
Ranjit, to Teddy Westside's kick-ass building.
我听不见你说啥哦
I cannot hear you.
我们五分钟后到
We will be there in five minutes.
拥有这孩子完全不代表你们很特别
This kid does not mean that you're special.
只代表了你很下流  你很淫荡
It just means that you're horny and you're easy.
废话少说  让老娘闻闻她头
Now, come on, let me smell his head.
莉莉  莉莉  别  别  别这样
Li-Lily, Lily, no, no, no, no, come on.
泰德  说真的  你这破地板是怎样啊
Seriously, Ted, what is up with the floor?
-莉莉  -干嘛
- Lily. - What?
离开马文的身边
Is it harder than we thought
比我们想象中难熬吗  的确
to be away from Marvin? Yes.
但我们今晚是要好好享乐  还是要蹲角落
But are we gonna have fun or are we gonna wallow
像白痴一样痛哭流涕呢
in the corner like idiots?
晚安  晚安  小马文 *
* Night, night, little Marvin
天上星星为你闪 *
* Stars twinkle for you
梦界火车嘎嚓飞 *
* The Dreamland train's a-chuggin'
你的梦想皆实现 *
* All your dreams will come true.
你意识到你脑海中构筑的东西
Do you realize that something you thought up in your head
现在真成为曼哈顿天际的一部分了吗
now exists as a part of the Manhattan skyline?
这很了不起呢
That's huge.
只是栋楼罢了
It's just a building.
我这么年轻就有如此成就  实属不易
I mean, I'm incredibly young for such an achievement,
但也只是栋楼罢了
but it's just a building.
虽然《建筑视野周报》
I mean, Architecture Vision Weekly
说我那楼"不仅仅是一栋楼"
may have dubbed it "more than just a building,"
但也就只是栋楼罢了
but it's just a building.
但也不用小题大...
So let's not get carried...
好啦  你说得对  的确很了不起
Okay, you're right, it's huge.
是很了得啊
It is huge.
你可是今晚派对的主角  更何况
You're the star of the party, and who knows?
说不定你未来的夫人也会在场呢
Maybe the future Mrs. Ted Mosby is gonna be there.
的确  说不定呢
Yeah, maybe she will.
等等  这不是你的楼
Wait, this isn't your...
这是环球新闻大楼
This is the World Wide News building.
把他追回来
Go get him.
都说我不想再去争取巴尼了
I told you, I am done chasing Barney.
我们可以去你派对了吗
Now can we please go to your party?
罗宾  你是想浪费一晚的时间
Robin, do you want to spend tonight
在我那前卫又不失高雅的神作大楼里
making small talk with a bunch of bankers
与一帮银行家们闲聊瞎扯呢
in a daring yet refined contemporary masterpiece
金刚也该为自己能爬那楼而感到荣幸
King Kong should feel lucky to climb...
还是你想跟随心之所愿
...or do you want to follow your heart?
你为何一直说我对巴尼还有感觉啊
Why do you keep insisting that I have feelings for Barney?
因为你确实还有
Because you do.
你看  兰吉特也这么认为
See, even Ranjit agrees.
原来他是要去尿尿
Oh, he's got to pee.
重点是
The point is,
你还忘不了巴尼
you're not over Barney.
所以你听到他要在环球新闻大楼顶
That's why you freaked out about him proposing
跟人求婚时  你反应超激动
on the roof of the World Wide News building.
我才没反应过激
I did not freak out.
只是有点...
It's just...
有点小小闹心
a teeny, tiny bit annoying
因为那地方
that I am the one
还是老娘带她认识的呢
who showed her that roof in the first place!
去你的  帕特里斯
Damn it, Patrice!
你...
Whoa.
"没事了  我找到个汽水瓶"
"Never mind; I found a soda bottle."
这也太恶心了
Okay, that's disturbing.
你想我怎么样啊  泰德
What do you want me to do, Ted?
冲上大楼顶
Run up to that roof,
把巴尼手上的求婚戒打飞
knock the ring out of Barney's hand,
然后说  "抱歉打扰了  但你该跟我在一起"
and say, "sorry to interrupt, but you should be with me"?
这不就是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
不是
No.
我不想要
I don't.
我不想老让自己当傻瓜
I can't keep making an ass of myself.
这个嘛
Well,
我要替"让自己当傻瓜"说句话
a word in defense of making an ass of yourself,
当傻瓜其实挺好的
it's underrated.
八年前
Eight years ago
我像个傻瓜一般地追你
I made an ass of myself chasing after you,
在那之后  我还继续多次让自己
and I've made an ass of myself chasing after you
像个傻瓜一样地追你
a bunch of times since then.
但我从没后悔过
But I have no regrets.
因为我得到了一件我千金也不换的东西
Because it led me to something that I wouldn't trade for the world.
那就是我们的友情
It led to you being my friend.
作为你的朋友
So, as your friend
以及"让自己当傻瓜"界的领衔人物
and a leading expert in the field of making an ass of yourself,
我打从心底
I say to you
想对你说
from the heart,
滚下这辆车
get the hell out of this car.
可是  泰德
But, Ted,
今晚是你的大日子
your big night.
只是栋楼罢了
It's just a building.
《罗宾》
The Robin.
第一步
Step one:
向她承认  自己还对她有感觉
admit to yourself that you still have feelings for this girl.
我无可救药地  义无反顾地爱着她
I am hopelessly, irretrievably in love with her.
而她却不知道我的爱有这么深
More than she knows.
第二步
Step two:
在最不适当的时刻  如刚从脱衣俱乐部出来
choose the completely wrong moment to make a drunken move
借着酒劲对她做出行动
after hanging out at a strip club
然后故意被她拒绝
and get shot down on purpose.
第三步
Step three:
同意你俩不合适
agree that you two don't work,
关上你们未来任何可能的大门
locking the door on any future you could have together.
我彻底放弃争取你了
I'm done trying to get you.
我无法再继续了
I can't do it anymore.
这会让罗宾疯掉
Which will drive Robin nuts.
第四步
Step four:
罗宾疯掉
Robin goes nuts.
第五步
Step five:
找出全世界最能激怒罗宾的人
find the person who annoys Robin most in the world...
没人叫你帮忙  帕特里斯
Nobody asked for your help, Patrice!
然后找她帮忙
...and ask for her help.
你好  巴尼
Oh, hi, Barney.
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
其实我是来找你的
Actually, I'm looking for you.
这事可能很怪  但我想请你帮我...
This may sound kind of weird, but I have a proposition...
向帕特里斯解释一切
Explain everything to Patrice
并希望她同意帮忙
and hope she agrees to help.
好啊  我爱罗宾
Yay. I love Robin.
我当然会帮你
Of course I'll help.
很好  很好
Good, good.
第六步
Step six:
找医生检查可能断裂的肋骨
check with your doctor about possible broken ribs.
第七步
Step seven:
假装跟帕特里斯约会
pretend to be dating Patrice.
没人请你来  帕特里斯
Nobody asked you here, Patrice!
是我请的
Actually, I did.
第八步
Step eight:
等着罗宾不出所料地闯入你家里
wait until Robin inevitably breaks into your place
找出《泡妞秘笈》  并拿给帕特里斯看
to find the Playbook and show it to Patrice,
而你可以从公寓里的隐藏摄像头
which you'll monitor via the hidden cameras
监视到这一切
you have in your apartment.
帕特里斯  罗宾入网了
Patrice, the robin's in the nest.
就是罗宾闯进我公寓的意思
That means Robin broke into my apartment
我解释暗号的时候  你有没有听啊
Were you even listening when I explained the codes?
第九步
Step nine:
在帕特里斯发现真有《泡妞秘籍》后
after Patrice finds the Playbook,
你们第一次大吵了一架
have your first big fight.
事情进展得太顺利了
This is going so well.
感激不尽啊
Thank you so much.
对啊  但为什么莉莉和泰德会在这里啊
I know, but what the heck are Lily and Ted doing here?
不知道  我朋友做人从没有界限
I don't know. My friends have no boundaries.
我该怎么感谢你啊
How can I ever thank you?
下周末能帮我照看下我的猫吗
Will you watch my cat next weekend?
不行
No.
走吧  我们该进去了
Come on, we should probably go back inside.
第十步
Step ten:
为了向帕特里斯表忠诚
prove your loyalty to Patrice
烧掉《泡妞秘籍》
by burning the Playbook,
然后就真的烧掉了
and actually burn it.
因为你再也不需要了
You don't need it anymore.
第十一步
Step 11:
因为你的朋友做人没有界限
because your friends have no boundaries,
他们肯定会给罗宾开个劝诫大会
they'll inevitably have an intervention for Robin,
而你可以通过藏在莉莉和马修公寓的
which you'll monitor via the hidden cameras
隐藏摄像头监视到这一切
you have in Marshall and Lily's apartment.
第十二步
Step 12:
只告诉泰德一个人  你打算跟帕特里斯求婚
tell only Ted about your plan to propose to Patrice.
你不能告诉任何人
You can't tell anybody.
同意吗
Agreed?
第十三步
Step 13:
坐等泰德是否会告诉罗宾
wait and see if Ted tells Robin,
如果他真说了...
and if he does...
巴尼要订婚了
Barney's getting engaged.
就意味着你全世界最好的兄弟
...it means your best bro in the world
已经彻底放下罗宾  并给予你他的祝福
has let go of Robin and has given you his blessing.
第十四步
Step 14:
罗宾来到这城市她最爱的地方
Robin arrives at her favorite spot in the city
并发现《泡妞秘籍》隐藏的最后一页
and finds the secret final page of the Playbook.
你泡妞生涯最后一次出招
The last play you'll ever run.
《罗宾》
第十五步
Step 15:
罗宾意识到自己站在槲寄生下面
Robin realizes she's standing underneath mistletoe.
在西方圣诞风俗中  站在槲寄生下的人不能拒绝亲吻
而在槲寄生下接吻的情侣将会幸福终生
你不是吧  巴尼
Seriously, Barney?
即使你是
Even you,
即使是像你这样不折不扣的疯子
even someone as certifiably insane as you
也该意识到  这么做太过分了吧
must realize that this is too far.
你欺骗我
You lied to me,
暗地里算计了我几周
manipulated me for weeks.
你觉得我知情后  我还会亲你吗
Do you really think I could ever kiss you after that?
你觉得我知情后  还会信任你吗
Do you really think I could ever trust you after that?
这个  就是我们俩不合适的证据
This... this is proof of why we don't work,
我们俩不可能在一起的原因
why we'll never work.
谢谢你
So thank you.
你让我自由了  因为...
You've set me free because...
我怎么可能会跟自以为用
how could I be with a man who thinks that this...
这种烂把戏  这种弥天大谎
trick, this enormous lie
就能让我想再次跟他约会的人一起
could ever make me want to date him again?
把那页翻过来
Turn it over.
第十六步  希望她会说"愿意"
罗宾・特布罗斯基
Robin Scherbatsky...
你愿意嫁给我吗
...will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
Fort Atlantic--《Let Your Heart Hold Fast》
穿过深邃的海洋 *
* In the oceans deep
越过险峻的峡谷 *
* In the canyons steep
我站在 *
* Walls of granite
坚如磐石的围墙前 *
* Here I stand
我所有绝望的呼喊 *
* All my desperate calls
在墙间回荡*
* Echo off the walls
久久不息 *
* Back and forth...
让我们举杯向泰德・莫斯比致敬
And so, let's all raise a glass to Ted Mosby.
我们有幸站在这里  全是他的功劳
None of this would have been possible without him.
敬泰德
To Ted.
相信自己踽踽独行 *
* To believe I walk alone
这是别人告诉我的谎言 *
* It's a lie that I've been told
不要灰心丧气 *
* So let your heart hold fast
因为这一切很快会过去 *
* For this soon shall pass
面前又将是人生的一座新山峰 *
* There's another hill ahead.